

San Francisco, CA · forest.r.welch@gmail.com · (415) 375-5162 · <u>LinkedIn</u> · <u>Github</u> · <u>forestsworld.me</u>

Queer bootcamp grad, linguist and polyglot, and former worldwide nomad with a strong background as a fullstack engineer. After taking a career break to tend to my health and navigate chronic illness and disability, I've been seeking employment in tech for almost 2 years. In my next role, I'm looking to explore new horizons and challenges, collaborate on high-impact projects, and grow in a supportive and diverse environment.

EXPERIENCE

BuildVision

San Francisco, CA

Software Engineer (Contract)

November 2023 - April 2024

- Spearheaded Next.js development for admin tools and customer views as BuildVision's second developer.
- Optimized data management and API interactions using RTK Query's cache tags, enhancing features like result
 caching, search filters, and inline editing.
- Created a comprehensive design system with NextUI, ensuring consistency and scalability across projects.

Autodesk (Formerly BuildingConnected)

 $Software\ Engineer$

San Francisco, CA August 2018 - January 2022

- Authored an org-wide React component library, reducing library size by ~30% and doubling functionality.
 - Unified disparate component libraries and JSS-in-CSS with styled-components, simplifying UI development.
 - Engineered common components including action menus, tables, and flyouts.
 - Documented props, usage, and design principles, accessible at design.buildingconnected.com.
- Directed a localization and internationalization initiative, expanding into Oceania and doubling the user base.
 - Implemented a centralized translation system using react-i18next, ensuring consistent localization.
 - Injected locale into server-side HTML templates for email and printer services for comprehensive localization.
- Rebuilt internal tools from the ground up, saving the Customer Success team 20 hours per week.
 - Converted UI from Angular to React for better performance, adding enhanced search and company merging.
 - Fixed a critical date picker bug, preventing contract expiration issues and saving millions of dollars.
- Managed the estimated cost feature initiative to empower contractors' decisions (used >5000 times weekly).
 - Crafted a comprehensive design document detailing approaches, requirements, and implementation plans.
 - Built reusable EstimatedCost component and memoized calculations with Redux's reselect for performance.
- Built a UserEvents tracking system, piping data to Snowflake for metrics via Mode Analytics.
- Conducted A/B testing with LaunchDarkly flags to optimize the onboarding flow, increasing successful sign ups.
- Streamlined the frontend CircleCI pipeline, reducing build and deployment times by 50%.
- Managed the frontend interview process, contributing to the successful hire of 5 engineers and 2 interns.
- Mentored two entry-level team members and an intern, providing structured onboarding and constructive feedback.
- Facilitated well-being initiatives during COVID-19, organizing yoga, meditation, and pair programming sessions.

EDUCATION

App Academy

San Francisco, CA

2018

Fullstack Engineering

University of Pennsylvania

Philadelphia, PA

B.A. in Linguistics, minor in Deaf Studies

2012 - 2016

SKILLS

Proficient: Familiar:

JavaScript, React, Next.js, Redux, Node.js, MongoDB, Git, CircleCI, LaunchDarkly, Mode Analytics TypeScript, React Native, Angular, PostgreSQL, Docker, Heroku, AWS, Elastic Cloud, Snowflake,

Redis, Mongoose, GraphQL, Jest, Cypress, Ruby on Rails, Webpack, jQuery